Barry Commoner Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Subject File, 1915-1978 (Box 205-321)
  - Education (Box 220)
    - General, 1954-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 221)
    - Science, 1948-1967 (Box 221)
  - Ehrlich, Paul, 1972, undated (Box 221)
  - Electricity, 1969-1973, undated, (3 folders) (Box 221)
  - Electron spin resonance and free radicals, circa 1945-circa 1965, (5 folders) (Box 222)
  - Electron spin resonance and free radicals, circa 1945-circa 1965, (2 folders) (Box 223)
  - Electrophoresis, 1929-1958, (4 folders) (Box 223)
  - Elsasser, Walter M., 1961-1965 (Box 224)
  - Energy book idea, 1972 (Box 224)
  - Energy conservation, 1970-1973, (3 folders) (Box 224)
  - Energy consumption, 1967-1974, (3 folders) (Box 224)
  - Energy crisis, 1971-1974, (2 folders) (Box 225)
  - Energy policy (Box 225)
    - 1967-1971, (4 folders) (Box 225)
    - 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 226)
  - Energy Policy Project, Washington, D.C., 1972-1974 (Box 226)
  - Energy Resource Center reference material log, 1974-1975 (Box 226)
  - Engineering, 1960-1967 (Box 226)
  - Engler, Richard, PHILAPOSH, 1974-1976, (2 folders) (Box 226)
  - Environmental conservation, 1964-1972, undated (Box 226)
  - Environmental conservation, 1964-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 227)
  - Environmental issues, 1966-1972, (4 folders) (Box 227)
  - Environmental issues, 1966-1972 (Box 228)
  - Environmental organizations, circa 1970-circa 1972, circa 1970-circa 1972DATE (Box 228)
  - Environmental pollution (Box 228)
    - Air, 1949-1972, (4 folders) (Box 228)
    - Air, 1949-1972, (3 folders) (Box 229)
    - Cadmium and zinc, 1970-1971 (Box 229)
    - Cities, 1966-1970 (Box 229)
    - Lead, 1965-1971, (2 folders) (Box 229)
    - Mercury, 1968-1972, (3 folders) (Box 230)
    - Noise, 1968-1972, (2 folders) (Box 230)
    - Polychlorinated biphenyls, 1972 (Box 230)
    - Water, 1966-1973 (Box 230)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 230)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, 1971 (Box 231)
  - Environmental publications, miscellaneous, 1968-1977, (2 folders) (Box 231)
  - Environmental Resources, Inc., 1972-1973 (Box 231)
  - Environmental Response, St. Louis, Mo., 1970-1975 (Box 231)
  - Enzymes, circa 1930-circa 1960, (2 folders) (Box 231)
  - Enzymes, circa 1930-circa 1960, (4 folders) (Box 232)
  - Esso Research and Engineering Company, 1955-1956 (Box 232)
  - Faraday Society, 1950-1954 (Box 232)
  - Federation of American Scientists, 1957-1975, (3 folders) (Box 232)
  - Federov, Evgenij K., 1973-1974 (Box 232)
  - Field Foundation, 1974-1975 (Box 232)
  - Flato, Charles, 1971-1974 (Box 233)
  - Fluoridation of drinking water, 1957, 1965-1973, (2 folders) (Box 233)
  - Food, 1959-1967 (Box 233)
  - Ford Foundation, 1967 (Box 233)
  - Foreign policy, 1965-1975 (Box 233)
  - Frasch Foundation, 1956-1967 (Box 233)
  - Gamarekian, Edward, Washington Post, 1959 (Box 234)
  - Gates, David M., 1965 (Box 234)
  - Geiger, Jack, 1970 (Box 234)
  - Genetics (Box 234)
    - Bennett, James M., dissertation, 1968 (Box 234)
    - DNA, 1950-1968, (3 folders) (Box 234)
    - DNA-RNA, 1959-1970, (2 folders) (Box 234)
    - Gene action/GP, 1936-1962, (3 folders) (Box 235)
    - General, circa 1925-circa 1965, (3 folders) (Box 235)
    - General, circa 1925-circa 1965, (6 folders) (Box 236)
    - General, circa 1925-circa 1965 (Box 237)
    - GP scientific articles, 1953-1961, (3 folders) (Box 237)
    - Plant viruses (Box 237)
      - 1915, 1927-1962, (3 folders) (Box 237)
      - 1950-1962, (2 folders) (Box 238)
    - RNA, 1955-1956, 1964-1965 (Box 238)
    - Tobacco plant, 1938-1958, (2 folders) (Box 238)
  - Geochemistry, 1949-1970 (Box 238)
  - Geochemistry, 1949-1970 (Box 239)
  - Geology and geotechnology, 1967-1969, undated (Box 239)
  - Goldstein, Norman N., 1962-1964 (Box 239)
  - Gordus, Adon, 1973 (Box 239)
  - Grant applications and proposals (Box 239)
    - 1962-1974, (3 folders) (Box 239)
    - 1973-1974, (2 folders) (Box 240)
  - Grant making institutions, 1950-1963 (Box 240)
  - Growth, circa 1935-circa 1960, (4 folders) (Box 240)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1973-1974 (Box 240)
  - Harvard University Program on Technology and Society, 1969-1971, (2 folders) (Box 241)
  - Hazardous materials, storage and transportation of, 1969 (Box 241)
  - Health issues, 1969-1971 (Box 241)
  - Heart disease, 1959-1966, (2 folders) (Box 241)
  - Hechter, Oscar, 1954-1963, (2 folders) (Box 241)
  - Hechter, Oscar, 1954-1963 (Box 242)
  - Heise, John, data, 1964-1965, undated (Box 242)
  - Herbicides, 1957, 1965-1970 (Box 242)
  - Hirst, Eric, 1974-1975 (Box 242)
  - Histochemical Society, 1952-1954 (Box 242)
  - Hoffman, Pat, Beaver Valley Power Station, Hookstown, Pa., 1974 (Box 242)
  - Hydrogen as fuel, 1971-1973 (Box 242)
  - Institute of Ecology, Chicago, Ill. (Box 242)
    - 1971, (2 folders) (Box 242)
    - 1971-1972, (2 folders) (Box 243)
  - Interior Department, 1962-1966 (Box 243)
  - International Council of Scientific Unions, 1970-1971 (Box 243)
  - Israel, 1972 (Box 243)
  - Italy, dioxin accident in Seveso, 1976-1978, (3 folders) (Box 243)
  - Journal of General Physiology, 1953, 1960 (Box 243)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1951-1961 (Box 243)
  - Journal of Theoretical Biology, 1960-1961 (Box 244)
  - Kitzbuhel-Vienna Conference of Scientists, 1958 (Box 244)
  - Kubie, Lawrence, 1953-1956, undated (Box 244)
  - L-Forms, 1962-1966 (Box 244)
  - Laboratory procedures, circa 1950-circa 1969 (Box 244)
  - Laucks, Irving F., circa 1960-1968, (3 folders) (Box 244)
  - Lyndon Baines Johnson Foundation, 1975 (Box 244)
  - Maleic hydrazide, 1967-1968 (Box 244)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass., 1970 (Box 244)
  - Mattison, Lindsay, 1976, undated (Box 244)
  - McCarthy, Carol, 1967, undated (Box 244)
  - McCarthy, Eugene, presidential campaign, 1967-1968 (Box 244)
  - McGovern, George, presidential campaign, 1972 (Box 245)
  - Mead, Margaret, 1965, 1970, 1978 (Box 245)
  - Media Project for Television and Radio, 1971-1973 (Box 245)
  - Medical research, 1960-1968, undated, (2 folders) (Box 245)
  - Mercury, 1966-1970, (2 folders) (Box 245)
  - Metabolism and electron transfer, circa 1935-circa 1955 (Box 245)
  - Metabolism and electron transfer, circa 1935-circa 1955, (2 folders) (Box 246)
  - Methanol fuel, 1973-1976 (Box 246)
  - Methemoglobin, 1958-1969, (2 folders) (Box 246)
  - Miscellaneous scientific articles, circa 1920-1959 (Box 246)
  - Miscellaneous scientific articles, circa 1920-1959, (6 folders) (Box 247)
  - Miscellaneous scientific articles, circa 1920-1959, (6 folders) (Box 248)
  - Miscellaneous scientific articles, circa 1920-1959 (Box 249)
  - Miscellaneous scientific articles, 1960-1972, (5 folders) (Box 249)
  - Miscellaneous scientific articles, 1960-1972, (5 folders) (Box 250)
  - Miscellany (Box 250)
    - 1959-1970, undated (Box 250)
    - 1971-1976, undated (Box 251)
  - Missouri, 1969-1971 (Box 251)
  - Missouri Botanical Garden, 1963-1969, (2 folders) (Box 251)
  - Monsanto Research Corp., 1962-1963 (Box 251)
  - Mussard, Jean A., 1972 (Box 251)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar, 1970-1971 (Box 251)
  - Nader, Ralph, 1966-1968 (Box 251)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1949, 1965-1971 (Box 251)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1949, 1965-1971, (2 folders) (Box 252)
  - National Air Conservation Commission, 1966-1969, (3 folders) (Box 252)
  - National Cancer Institute, 1963 (Box 252)
  - National Council for the Environment, 1971 (Box 252)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis (Box 253)
    - Budgets, 1951-1965 (Box 253)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1963, (4 folders) (Box 253)
    - Grant applications, 1953-1965, (2 folders) (Box 253)
    - Grant applications, 1953-1965, (3 folders) (Box 254)
    - Reports, 1953-1963, (4 folders) (Box 254)
  - National Parks Association, 1968-1972, (6 folders) (Box 255)
  - National Parks Association, 1968-1972, (6 folders) (Box 256)
  - National Parks Association, 1968-1972 (Box 257)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 257)
    - 1959-1971, (6 folders) (Box 257)
    - 1965-1969, (9 folders) (Box 258)
    - 1970-1973, 1970-1971 (Box 259)
  - National Wildlife, 1970-1971 (Box 259)
  - Nature magazine, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 259)
  - New publications announcements and lists, 1969-1972, (2 folders) (Box 259)
  - Nitrates and nitrites, circa 1960-circa 1970, (2 folders) (Box 259)
  - Nitrogen cycle, 1958-1970 (Box 260)
  - Nitrogen fertilizer, circa 1955-circa 1970, circa 1950-circa 1970 (Box 260)
  - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1973 (Box 260)
  - Normal Soil, Inc., 1953-1969 (Box 260)
  - Nuclear power (Box 260)
    - 1961-1970, (4 folders) (Box 260)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 261)
  - Nuclear reactors, 1968-1969 (Box 261)
  - Nuclear test ban, circa 1955-circa 1965, 1972 (Box 261)
  - Nuclear war, circa 1955-circa 1970, (2 folders) (Box 261)
  - Nuclear weapons testing (Box 261)
    - 1956-1967, 1956-1957 (Box 261)
    - 1956-1971, (3 folders) (Box 262)
  - Nucleic acids, circa 1940-circa 1960, (2 folders) (Box 262)
  - Nucleic acids, circa 1940-circa 1960, (3 folders) (Box 263)
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Oak Ridge, Tenn., 1973-1974 (Box 263)
  - Oil companies (Box 263)
    - General, 1970-1975 (Box 263)
    - Pipelines, 1970-1971 (Box 263)
  - Oliver, James, 1973-1975 (Box 263)
  - Oparin, Alexander Ivanovich, 1968-1976 (Box 263)
  - Origin of life, 1953-1970 (Box 263)
  - Origin of life, 1953-1970 (Box 264)
  - Outer space, circa 1960-circa 1970, (5 folders) (Box 264)
  - Patents and legal papers, 1954-1960 (Box 264)
  - Patents and legal papers, 1954-1960, (2 folders) (Box 265)
  - Pauling, Linus (Box 265)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1968 (Box 265)
    - Miscellany, 1958-1965, 1976 (Box 265)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1957-1963 (Box 265)
  - Peaceful uses of atomic energy (Box 265)
    - Electric power, 1963-1970, (2 folders) (Box 265)
    - Miscellany, 1953-1970 (Box 265)
    - Project Chariot, 1959-1966 (Box 265)
    - Project Plowshare, 1958-1967, undated, Project Plowshare, undated; (3 folders) (Box 266)
    - Safety standards, 1957-1970 (Box 266)
    - Seaborg, Glenn, 1969-1972 (Box 266)
  - Penn Central Transportation Co., 1971-1974, (4 folders) (Box 266)
  - Penn Central Transportation Co., 1971-1974, (6 folders) (Box 267)
  - Penn Central Transportation Co., 1971-1974, (2 folders) (Box 268)
  - People with interest in action, undated (Box 268)
  - Perelman, Michael, 1972-1973, undated (Box 268)
  - Perkin-Elmer Corp. consulting, 1965-1967 (Box 268)
  - Permission to print or quote (Box 268)
    - 1965-1971, (3 folders) (Box 268)
    - 1972 (Box 269)
  - Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 1963-1964 (Box 269)
  - Pesticides, circa 1960-circa 1972, (4 folders) (Box 269)
  - Phenyklentonuria (PKU), 1965-1967 (Box 269)
  - Philosophy, 1958-1969 (Box 269)
  - Photosynthesis, circa 1930-circa 1960, (6 folders) (Box 270)
  - Photosynthesis, circa 1940-circa 1960, (4 folders) (Box 271)
  - Phototropism and photosynthesis, 1960-1962, undated (Box 271)
  - Plant physiologists, 1946-1965 (Box 271)
  - Plant physiology, 1935-1958 (Box 271)
  - Plant physiology, 1935-1958, (3 folders) (Box 272)
  - Plant substances, 1926-1960, (4 folders) (Box 272)
  - Plastics and plasticizers, 1971-1972 (Box 273)
  - Pocket photocopying device, 1962-1965 (Box 273)
  - Polyatomic radicals, 1964 (Box 273)
  - Population growth (Box 273)
    - Center for Population Research, Bethesda, Md., 1971 (Box 273)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 273)
    - Environmental issues and population, circa 1960-1972, (2 folders) (Box 273)
    - Explosion, 1963, 1970, undated (Box 273)
    - Family planning, 1965-1971 (Box 273)
    - Food, 1963-1971 (Box 274)
    - General (Box 274)
      - circa 1960-1972, (6 folders) (Box 274)
      - 1970-1974 (Box 275)
    - International development, 1972-1974 (Box 275)
    - The Population Council, 1970-1971 (Box 275)
    - World Population Conference, Budapest, Hungary, 1974 (Box 275)
  - Positions available elsewhere, 1966-1972, (2 folders) (Box 275)
  - Power plants, 1967-1971, (2 folders) (Box 275)
  - Presidential campaign for Johnson-Humphrey, 1964 (Box 276)
  - Proteins, 1940-1959, (5 folders) (Box 276)
  - Public health, 1966-1972 (Box 276)
  - Publishers, 1966-1969 (Box 276)
  - Pugwash Conference, Oxford, England, 1971-1972 (Box 277)
  - Questionnaires, 1966-1972, (2 folders) (Box 277)
  - Radiation (Box 277)
    - Effects of, 1956-1970 (Box 277)
    - General (Box 277)
      - 1926-1958, (3 folders) (Box 277)
      - 1959-1970, (3 folders) (Box 278)
    - Irradiation, 1953, 1963-1967 (Box 278)
    - Nuclear power, 1969-1970 (Box 278)
    - Strontium-90, 1956-1968, (2 folders) (Box 278)
  - Radioactive fallout (Box 279)
    - Agriculture, 1961-1965, (2 folders) (Box 279)
    - General, 1956-1963, (4 folders) (Box 279)
    - General, 1956-1963, (3 folders) (Box 280)
    - Health and Safety Laboratory, U. S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1958-1967 (Box 280)
    - Iodine 131, 1958-1967 (Box 280)
    - Knapp, Harold, 1962-1965 (Box 280)
    - Organizations, 1959-1963, undated (Box 280)
    - Slaughterhouse project, 1942, 1958-1962, undated (Box 281)
    - Strontium-90 in milk, 1958-1966, (2 folders) (Box 281)
  - Religion, 1966-1970 (Box 281)
  - Requests to review manuscripts, 1966-1969 (Box 281)
  - Research notes (Box 281)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 281)
    - 1939-1965, (4 folders) (Box 282)
    - 1950-1965, (6 folders) (Box 283)
    - 1953-1958, (5 folders) (Box 284)
    - 1953-1958, (6 folders) (Box 285)
    - 1955-1958, (6 folders) (Box 286)
    - 1957-1962, (5 folders) (Box 287)
    - 1958, (4 folders) (Box 288)
    - 1958-1965, (6 folders) (Box 289)
    - 1960-1968, (4 folders) (Box 290)
    - 1962-1970, (5 folders) (Box 291)
    - 1965-1968, (2 folders) (Box 292)
  - Resources, Canadian Council of Resource Ministers, 1967-1969 (Box 292)
  - River research proposal, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 292)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund Environmental Agenda Task Force report, 1976, (2 folders) (Box 292)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 292)
    - 1948-1960, (2 folders) (Box 292)
    - 1950-1960, (2 folders) (Box 293)
  - Rodell, Marie, literary agent, 1964-1969 (Box 293)
  - Royal Swedish Academy of Sciences, symposium on nitrogen, 1973-1976, (3 folders) (Box 293)
  - Ruder and Finn, New York, N.Y., 1972-1973 (Box 293)
  - Rubinow, Ray, Kaplan Fund, 1975 (Box 293)
  - Savane, Landing, 1975-1976 (Box 294)
  - Schneider, Stephen H., climate change, 1974-1975 (Box 294)
  - Science magazine, 1964-1968 (Box 294)
  - Science and the public, 1946, 1958-1972, (5 folders) (Box 294)
  - Science Year, Field Enterprises, 1966-1969, (3 folders) (Box 295)
  - The Sciences, 1971 (Box 295)
  - Scientific equipment (Box 295)
    - Baird Atomic, 1951, 1959 (Box 295)
    - Bellco Glass, Inc., 1957-1959, undated (Box 295)
    - Beckman Instruments, 1952-1962 (Box 295)
    - Cary Spectrometer, 1956-1958 (Box 295)
    - General (Box 295)
      - 1949-1960, (2 folders) (Box 295)
      - 1961-1966, undated, (2 folders) (Box 296)
    - Laser, 1962 (Box 296)
    - Science Tools, 1959-1961 (Box 296)
  - Scientists Committee for Voter Information, 1964 (Box 296)
  - Scientists Committee on Loyalty Problems, 1949 (Box 296)
  - Seabrook nuclear power plant, N.H., 1978 (Box 296)
  - Semiconductors, 1963 (Box 296)
  - Sewage, 1969 (Box 296)
  - Sheinbaum, Stanley K., 1975-1976 (Box 296)
  - Sidel, Victor, Montefiore Hospital, Bronx, N.Y., 1975 (Box 296)
  - Slaner, Alfred, 1974-1975 (Box 296)
  - Social problems, 1964-1968 (Box 296)
  - Society of General Physiologists (Box 296)
    - 1955-1962, (2 folders) (Box 296)
    - 1963-1970 (Box 297)
  - Soil, 1970-1973 (Box 297)
  - Soil Association, Suffolk, England, 1965-1972, (2 folders) (Box 297)
  - Solar energy, 1960-1975, (3 folders) (Box 297)
  - Solar energy, 1960-1975, (8 folders) (Box 298)
  - Solar energy, 1960-1975, (7 folders) (Box 299)
  - Solar energy, 1960-1975, (4 folders) (Box 300)
  - Solid waste, 1969-1972, (2 folders) (Box 300)
  - Sponsorships declined, 1966-1968 (Box 300)
  - St. Louis, Mo. (Box 300)
    - Air pollution, 1962-1972 (Box 300)
    - Miscellany, 1964-1973, undated (Box 300)
    - Public school system, 1962-1964 (Box 300)
    - Public school system, 1962-1964 (Box 301)
  - Stamler, Jeremiah, Committee for Preserving Constitutional Rights, 1965-1969, (2 folders) (Box 301)
  - Student environmental congresses and teach-ins, 1964-1970 (Box 301)
  - Study group on the unity of knowledge, 1966-1969 (Box 301)
  - Supersonic transport (Box 301)
    - General, 1964-1971, (3 folders) (Box 301)
    - Interior Department special study group on the sonic boom in relation to man, 1967-1969, (3 folders) (Box 302)
  - Szent-Gyorgi, Albert, 1957-1962, 1974 (Box 302)
  - Technology, 1969-1970, undated (Box 302)
  - Tobacco mosaic virus (Box 302)
    - Biology, 1915-1962, (2 folders) (Box 302)
    - Biology, 1934-1969, (7 folders) (Box 303)
    - Chemistry, 1920-1962, (6 folders) (Box 304)
    - Miscellany, 1954-1955, 1968-1972, undated (Box 304)
  - Translations, 1950-1952, 1964, undated (Box 304)
  - Transportation Department, 1971-1973 (Box 304)
  - Travel accounts (Box 305)
    - 1964-1969, (7 folders) (Box 305)
    - 1969-1971, (6 folders) (Box 306)
    - 1971, (2 folders) (Box 307)
  - United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America, 1972-1973 (Box 307)
  - United Nations (Box 307)
    - Conference on the Human Environment, Stockholm, Sweden, 1971-1972, (3 folders) (Box 307)
    - Fano, Enzo, 1975 (Box 307)
  - United States Air Force Office of Scientific Research, 1964-1967 (Box 307)
  - United States Congress (Box 307)
    - McCarthy, Richard D., press releases, 1969-1970 (Box 307)
    - Miscellany (Box 307)
      - 1963-1969 (Box 307)
      - 1970-1971, (2 folders) (Box 308)
    - Mosher, Charles A., 1965 (Box 308)
    - Senate correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 308)
    - Senate Subcommittee on Air and Water Pollution (Box 308)
      - Correspondence and press releases, 1967-1971 (Box 308)
      - Draft testimonies, 1967-1969, (2 folders) (Box 308)
  - United States Office of Naval Research (Box 308)
    - Contract file (Box 308)
      - 1950-1951, (2 folders) (Box 308)
      - 1952-1959, (8 folders) (Box 309)
      - 1960-1970, (8 folders) (Box 310)
    - Equipment, 1964-1971 (Box 311)
    - Instructions and information, 1958-1967 (Box 311)
    - Manuscripts for publication, 1954-1960 (Box 311)
  - Unity of knowledge study group, 1967-1968 (Box 311)
  - University Academy, University City, Mo., 1968 (Box 311)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1965 (Box 311)
  - University of Massachusetts proposal for Institute on Man and his Environment, 1970 (Box 311)
  - University of Oklahoma Law Center Commission, Norman, Okla. (Box 311)
    - 1967-1969, (3 folders) (Box 311)
    - 1969-1970, (2 folders) (Box 312)
  - Urban problems, 1965-1969 (Box 312)
  - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission (Box 312)
    - Environment, 1973, (3 folders) (Box 312)
    - Fallout, 1959-1971 (Box 312)
    - Fission reactors, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 313)
    - Fusion energy, 1973, (3 folders) (Box 313)
    - Health and safety manual, 1965-1971, (2 folders) (Box 313)
    - Liquid metal fast breeder reactors, 1971 (Box 313)
    - Liquid metal fast breeder reactors, 1974, (5 folders) (Box 314)
    - Liquid metal fast breeder reactors, 1974, (5 folders) (Box 315)
    - Liquid metal fast breeder reactors, 1974, (4 folders) (Box 316)
    - Multi-directional research, 1973, (2 folders) (Box 316)
    - Solar energy, 1973-1974 (Box 316)
    - Transportation systems, 1973, (3 folders) (Box 317)
  - Vietnam War, opposition to (Box 317)
    - Citizens' White Paper, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 317)
    - The Crisis, Committee to End the War in Vietnam, Madison, Wis., 1965-1966, (2 folders) (Box 317)
    - Holmquist, Pea, 1965-1972, (2 folders) (Box 317)
    - "The Kissinger-Nixon Doctrine: A Guide to Disaster," 1971 (Box 318)
    - Law suit, 1972 (Box 318)
    - Miscellany, 1968-1971 (Box 318)
    - Student strike, 1967-1970 (Box 318)
  - Virology, 1965-1969, (3 folders) (Box 318)
  - Virus, 1930-1949 (Box 318)
  - Virus, 1930-1960, (7 folders) (Box 319)
  - Visitors, 1964-1966 (Box 319)
  - Washington Monthly Company, 1972 (Box 320)
  - Water, 1964-1972, (4 folders) (Box 320)
  - Weather modification, 1966-1973, (3 folders) (Box 320)
  - Wind power, 1974-1979 (Box 320)
  - Wine, 1969-1970, undated (Box 321)
  - Zoology, 1967-1968 (Box 321)
- Organizations File, 1919-1980 (Box 321-441)
  Organizations that Commoner either founded, had leadership positions in, or was heavily involved with. This series also includes material from his faculty years at Washington University in St. Louis, Missouri.
  Material types include correspondence, reports, committee papers, speeches and events material, financial records, and other related material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization into the following subseries: American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), Center for the Biology of Natural Systems (CBNS), Committee for Environmental Information CEI), Greater St. Louis Citizens' Committee for Nuclear Information (CNI), Scientsts' Institute for Public Information (SIPI), and Washington University.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1919-1975 (Box 321-379)
    The files primarily pertain to the AAAS committees in which Commoner was most active: the Committee on the Social Aspects of Science, the Committee on Science in the Promotion of Human Welfare, and the Committee on Environmental Alterations. These particular AAAS committees worked to engage scientists in public policy issues such as radioactive fallout from nuclear weapons testing, air quality, and energy consumption. Also present are files on annual meetings, the board of directors, budgets, and AAAS publications. Prominent correspondents include Chauncey Leake, Margaret Mead, Ward Pigman, and Dael Wolfle. More files pertaining to the AAAS are in both the 1990 and 2019 Additions.
    Material types include correspondence, draft writings, committee reports and publications, financial records, minutes of meetings, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by committee name, topic, or material type.
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Regional Centers, 1972 (Box 321)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Support of Scientific Research, 1971-1972 (Box 321)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Women, 1971-1972 (Box 321)
    - Annual meetings (Box 321)
      - 1952-1955, (5 folders) (Box 321)
      - 1956-1962, (9 folders) (Box 322)
      - 1964-1970, (7 folders) (Box 323)
      - 1971-1972, (6 folders) (Box 324)
      - 1973-1975, (6 folders) (Box 325)
    - Arden House, 1951, 1971-1972 (Box 325)
    - Board of Directors (Box 326)
      - 1966-1969, (8 folders) (Box 326)
      - 1970-1971, (6 folders) (Box 327)
      - 1971-1973, 1971-1975; (6 folders) (Box 328)
      - 1973-1974, (3 folders) (Box 329)
    - British Association for the Advancement of Science, 1968-1969 (Box 329)
    - Budgets and operating expenses (Box 329)
      - 1963-1972, (3 folders) (Box 329)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 330)
    - Chemical warfare in Vietnam, 1966-1970, (4 folders) (Box 330)
    - Clippings, 1957-1966 (Box 330)
    - Commission on Air Conservation, 1962-1965 (Box 330)
    - Commission on Air Conservation, 1962-1965, (4 folders) (Box 331)
    - Commission on Science Education, 1967-1973 (Box 331)
    - Committee on Arid Lands, 1954-1974 (Box 331)
    - Committee on Council Affairs, 1961-1974, (4 folders) (Box 332)
    - Committee on Environmental Alterations (Box 332)
      - Advertisements, 1971-1972 (Box 332)
      - African Americans, 1971-1973 (Box 332)
      - Agriculture, 1961-1971 (Box 332)
      - Agriculture, 1961-1971 (Box 333)
      - Air-conditioning, 1971-1972 (Box 333)
      - Alaska, 1969-1972 (Box 333)
      - Aluminum, 1964-1972, (2 folders) (Box 333)